Alex J. Martin

Rancho Cucamonga, California 91730 caalexmartin@gmail.com • 909.933.0027 (c)

Profile

Extensive management background with in-depth experience overseeing vendor relationships and operations for corporate events. Skilled at cultivating client relationships, quickly and efficiently identifying and resolving issues. Demonstrated expertise developing and implementing revenue generating strategies and initiatives, staffing events ranging from small local proceedings to large national events.

Professional Experience

Road to California, Ontario, California

Show Manager, 2014-Present

Coordinate and monitor daily operations for 250+ vendors and 500+ vendor booths during annual conference drawing more than 39,000 attendees. Manage staff responsible for event coordination activities.

- Manage event details, including the sales of vendor booths of varying locations for three separate buildings, compliant with building specifications and city codes.
- Maintain and develop vendor relationships, resolving disputes and managing issues among vendors, increasing vendor satisfaction by 8%.
- Designed and developed innovative digital branding strategy, increasing website traffic substantially through ease of use.

BMT Staffing Solutions, Atlanta, Georgia

Staffing Manager, 2012–2013

Managed staffing for events ranging from small street teams to full convention support staff. Cultivated excellent client relationships, assessing needs and wants for upcoming promotions and interviewing, screening, and hiring temporary staff for both local and national events.

 Supervised and trained teams of two to 400+ staff, ensuring compliance with job duties and company standards.

Trophy Club, Atlanta, Georgia

Assistant Manager, 2010–2012

Served as primary point of contact for all members; governing sales, concerns, due collections, and other membership issues for golf club with \$2.4M operating budget. Utilized periodic financial reports to manage expenses and operating costs.

- Developed and implemented revenue-generating strategies, increasing rounds membership and improving merchandise sales.
- Supervised team of 15+ employees, scheduling, monitoring performance, and disciplining as needed.
- Coordinated new hire onboarding, overseeing recruiting, training, and mentoring new hires.

Alex J. Martin • Page 2

• Improved overall sales by 7.5% in 2011 by creating guest-oriented brand and cultivating positive work environment through communication, vision, and teamwork.

Education and Credentials

Coursework in English and Business, 2004 Chaffey College – Rancho Cucamonga, California

Technical Proficiencies

Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook)

Adobe Creative Suite (Acrobat, Illustrator, Photoshop, Muse, Dreamweaver)